JESSIE TARROSA

REACT DEVELOPER

Gorordo Ave, Cebu, Ph 09192106060 creators.nuke@gmail.com

PROFILE SUMMARY

Three years of professional experience as a Front End Developer with proficiency in HTML, CSS, SASS, Bootstrap, Typescript, Javascript, AWS, SQL, JSON, and PHP. Familiar with React, Redux, Express, Laravel, Wordpress, Git, SQL, and MongoDB. Focuses on building tools and features to help business grow. Currently working as React Developer using latest technology to improve interface and interaction with the end-user.

Core Programming Language (in years): JavaScript (3)

Core Framework: ReactJS (3), Redux (3)

Core Database: MySQL (1), MongoDB (2), Firebase (1)

Additional Skills: Serverless NodeJS (2), AWS Lambda Development (1), TypeScript (1), ExpressJS (2), DevOps (1), AWS (1), JSON (2), SaaS (2), CSS (3), HTML (3), Git (3), Github (3), JIRA (1), Postman (1), Login Authentication API Integration (1), CrudAPI (1), Paypal (0.6), Payment API Integration (0.6)

WORK EXPERIENCE

React Developer March 2022 - Present

Codev

- Designed frontend applications using web technologies
- Using ESlint for ensuring code quality
- · Creating functions and components and unit test
- Creating responsive design (small to big screen)
- Worked in designing the CSS templates for use in all pages, components
- Troubleshooting and debugging code application
- Using github and GIT for version control
- Meeting with the development team to discuss user interface ideas and features
- CI/CD

Technology: React, Javascript, Typescript, NodeJS, Redux, Material UI, SCSS, CSS

Advanced App Engineering Analyst / React Developer

July 2021 - March 2022

Accenture Inc

- Designed and developed frontend applications using web technologies
- Developed single page application using React
- Setting up application state using context, redux
- Implemented redux with actions and reducers to implement a sync api calls
- Using Redux toolkit for state application
- Creating Slices, actions and reducers to implement a sync api calls
- Creating functions, components and custom components
- Involved in unit testing using testing-library, mocha, chai
- Code rewrite from javascript to typescript
- Using JWT authentions and handling cookies with several third party API

- Troubleshooting and debugging code application
- Reviews codes and PR
- Creating responsive design (small to big screen)
- Worked in designing the CSS templates for use in all pages, components
- · Using JIRA for bug tracking and ESLint for ensuring code quality
- Using AWS amplify authentication
- Using AWS Code Repo to tracked branches
- Using AWS Cloudfront to deploy the Application
- Using AWS Redshift
- Using AWS Serverless to built and deploy application API
- Using ChartJS and creating plugins
- CI/CD

Technology: React, Javascript, Typescript, NodeJS, SCSS, Bootstrap, Material UI, CSS, Redux, Serverless Lambda, AWS, Redshift, SQL, JIRA, ChartJS

Fullstack Developer

January 2020 - June 2021

Freelance

- Designed and developed frontend applications using web technologies
- Developed single page application using React
- Setting up application state using context, redux
- Implemented redux with actions and reducers to implement a sync api calls
- Creating functions and components and unit test
- Worked with Restful API using express
- Worked with database using MongoDB
- Implemented backend web API and established connectivity with use of axios
- Using GIT for version control
- Worked in designing the CSS templates for use in all pages, components
- Create Custom Component for data manipulation and to display data in standard format
- Troubleshooting and debugging code application
- Using hooks for the theme application and api calls

Technology: React, Javascript, Express, NodeJS, Redux, Paypal API, SQL, MongoDB, Third-party API, Material UI, SCSS, CSS

Web Developer/Graphic Designer

May 2015 - May 2016

Landasia Real Estate and Development Corp

- Create Landing Page
- Creating Subpages for marketing and posting available properties
- Setting up subdomain pages
- Creating responsive design (small to big screen)
- · Creating and maintaining business pages
- Designing brochures, tarpaulins, magazine and flyers
- Troubleshooting and debugging code application

Technology: PHP, Wordpress, HTML, CSS, Javascript, Photoshop, Adobe Illustrator

EDUCATION